Face the evil.
Fear Street: 1994 is a horror, mystery film directed by Leigh Janiak.
After a series of brutal slayings, a teen and her friends take on an evil
force that's plagued their notorious town for centuries.
Deena, played by Kiana Madeira.
Samantha Fraser, played by Olivia Scott Welch.
Josh, played by Benjamin Flores Jr..
Kate, played by Julia Rehwald.
Simon, played by Fred Hechinger.
Heather, played by Maya Hawke.
Fear Street Part One: 1994 (titled onscreen as Fear Street 1994) is a 2021
American supernatural slasher film directed by Leigh Janiak.
The first installment in the Fear Street trilogy, the film was written by Phil Graziadei and Janiak from a
story by Kyle Killen, Graziadei, and Janiak, based on the book series of the same name by R.
The film follows a teen and her friends after a series of brutal slayings, as they take
on an evil force that has plagued their notorious town for centuries.
It stars Kiana Madeira, Olivia Scott Welch, Benjamin Flores Jr., Julia Rehwald, Fred
Hechinger, Ashley Zukerman, Darrell Britt-Gibson, and Maya Hawke.
Development of a film based on Fear Street began in 1997 when Hollywood Pictures
acquired the rights to the series, but the project never materialized.
It re-entered development at 20th Century Fox in 2015, with Janiak hired to
direct and rewrite Killen's script with Graziadei in 2017.
Produced by Chernin Entertainment, filming for the trilogy took place back-to-back from March to
September 2019 in Georgia, with the film set for a theatrical release in June 2020.
However, the trilogy was pulled from the schedule
because of the COVID-19 pandemic.
Following the acquisition of 21st Century Fox by Disney, Chernin Entertainment ended their distribution
deal with 20th Century Studios and gave distribution rights to Netflix in August 2020.
Fear Street Part One: 1994 premiered at the Los Angeles State Historic Park on June 28, 2021, and was released on
Netflix on July 2, 2021, with the other entries, Part Two: 1978 and Part Three: 1666, released weekly.
The film received generally positive reviews.
The film explores themes of witch, based on novel or
book, shopping mall, murder, curse.
The tone is dark and mind_bending.